WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.
A telegram for Lady Edith.
Oh, you should go.
What about you?
No, not really.
I don't want to disturb you. Don't be
silly. You couldn't disturb me.
Thank you, Baxter.
I wouldn't have bothered you. Stop
talking like that and move back in.
I only came to tell you that Edith's
about to receive some bad news. What?
How do you know?
Her editor's on his way here.
It's what we've been waiting for.
However much you expect it,
it's still painful when it arrives.
You don't think it's good news?
If it were, he'd have telephoned.
When you see Madge, warn her.
Are you all set for tomorrow?
What's this?
I'm going to see the cottage again,
and then I have to make up my mind.
Mrs Hughes is coming with me.
I'll leave you to it.
What's it like, this cottage?
I don't know.
You can ask me after tomorrow.
Unless you want to come with us?
She wouldn't want me.
You know that's not true.
It'd be good to
bury the memorial business.
See what she says -
but don't force her.
Of course it's terrible,
but what did she think he was doing?
Living in a tree?
You mustn't make jokes, Milady.
Only in here. I'll be
as solemn as a church when I go down.
No, I am sorry, truly.
He was a nice man.
Though what he saw in Edith, I...
Goodness. The York and Ainsty
are holding a point-to-point
at Canningford Grange on Saturday,
and Mr Blake has persuaded Lord
Gillingham they should ride in it.
Don't you have to follow the hunt to be eligible?
They've been out with the York and Ainsty.
They'll have wangled it. I might join them.
Are ladies allowed to race with the men?
It changed just before the war.
Papa thinks it terribly fast.
Do they want to stay here,
Mr Blake and Lord Gillingham?
They want to meet at Canningford
and then come here that night. Golly.
Why would His Lordship come here
after you've broken it off?
Because he still won't accept
I know my own mind.
Anna, do you think
I'm looking rather frumpy?
Certainly not, Milady.
Hm.
I'm tempted to remind them
of what they're missing.
You'd never be that heartless.
Shrimpie says he's narrowing the list
of possibilities,
and he thinks he'll track her down
before long.
Are you going to tell the prince?
I think I should, don't you?
Would you like me to come?
No. I'll go alone this time.
Oh. I'm ever so sorry, Milady,
I didn't know you had company.
This is Mrs Crawley, my cousin.
You'll find she's a frequent visitor.
Good day, Madam.
Hello.
Denker is my new maid.
She's trying to find her way around.
Did you have a question, Denker?
It can wait, Milady.
Well, I was going to ask you about
the luggage,
and which cases you prefer
when you travel.
Why, I don't travel much these days.
Why don't you ask Spratt?
He'll help you.
Oh, he'll help me, will he? Hmm.
That's good to know.
If you'll excuse me.
Honestly, Mr Barrow, take some time
off and have a rest. You look dreadful.
I'm fine, thank you. I've never felt
better. You've never looked worse.
Since you are indifferent
to my opinions, Mr Bates,
it's only fitting I am indifferent to
yours. I'm nipping to the cottage.
- I've left my button box there.
- Oh, that's Lady Mary.
She must want something before lunch.
You go, I'll fetch it.
Would you? Thank you.
Do we know when he'll get here?
Later this afternoon.
I should have some drawings for you all to
look at before long. What sort of drawings?
Ideas for how we could renovate the run-down village
houses. Why is there such a building spurt?
The war showed how half
the population were badly housed.
They were shocked by how unhealthy
some of the new recruits were.
"You cannot expect to get an A1
population out of C3 homes."
Who said that?
I think it was on a poster.
I heard from Charles today.
He and Tony are competing
in the point-to-point at Canningford
on Saturday.
Atticus was talking about that.
Atticus?
Atticus Aldridge, the chap I met in
York. Has he become a friend?
Yes. His parents, the Sinderbys,
have bought Canningford Grange.
Now they're wooing the county.
Lord Sinderby's rich, isn't he?
Who'd take it on if they weren't?
Why don't we all go, make a day of
it? We could ask Granny and Isobel
and take the children. Shall I tell
Charles they can stay here?
Course, if you want them to.
When this fellow arrives, it would be nice if you
could leave Edith and me to see him on our own.
This must be it. Ah.
Really, Milady? You do surprise me.
I hope your standards are
not so high as to prevent you
remaining in my employment, Denker.
No, not at all.
Not as high as that, Milady.
Where's the...?
Where's the knocker?
You... You stay here.
I've shown him
into the drawing room,
but I'm afraid it is as we feared.
Oh, I am sorry.
His Lordship's with them now.
He's here, then?
Yes, and it's not looking hopeful.
Oh, dear. Mrs Hughes says
you want to come with us tomorrow.
Only if you wouldn't mind.
This is the olive branch, I suppose?
If it's too much trouble -
No, no.
You can buy the tea.
Mr Carson wants to see the cottage.
He wants you to forgive him.
Why don't you come too?
I've got work to do.
You seem to be working harder
than when Miss Bunting was around.
I am.
I'm determined not to let her down.
Some tea? I can just about make tea.
How did you find me?
Rose gave me your address.
And you came alone
to this part of the city?
I was accompanied by my maid.
She's waiting outside.
How wonderful to be back in a world
where ladies are
accompanied by their maids.
Why didn't your son provide you
with a car?
Oh, he would have done. I just didn't
choose to tell him where I was going.
It is not our first
secret assignation.
I always feel more comfortable...
leaving the past in the past.
Then why have you come?
Because Rose's father,
Lord Flintshire,
thinks he's close
to finding the Princess.
She's alive, then? She was alive
when she left Russia. That they know.
They think she was put on a boat
headed for Hong Kong.
You'll know more soon.
I wanted you
from the moment I first saw you.
More than mortal man
ever wanted woman.
That is an historical detail.
Nonsense.
If Irena were dead, I would ask you
to run away with me now.
You couldn't run away
when there's no-one left
to "run away" from.
I loved you more than I loved her.
Even today.
Even this afternoon.
Please don't.
Why not,
if it's true?
Because you'll make it sound as if
we were both unhappy,
and I don't believe you were -
and I certainly was not.
You wouldn't admit it
if it were true.
You think to be unhappy
in a marriage...is ill-bred.
You do know me, Igor.
That I must concede.
Yes.
Who was that?
Sergeant Willis.
He wants to come back with that man
from Scotland Yard.
I don't like the sound of it.
Is it to see Mr Bates again?
That's the funny thing.
He wants to see Miss Baxter
this time. Miss Baxter?
What's she got to say about it?
Search me.
When are they coming?
Tomorrow morning.
I hope they don't stay all day -
or we'll miss our appointment.
He's gone.
Didn't he want some tea?
I offered him tea, dinner and a bed for
the night, but he had to get back.
Gregson's dead, I'm afraid.
How terrible that is to hear.
And was it this Herr Hitler?
Apparently.
Or at least his gang of thugs,
during the so-called
Bierkeller Putsch in Munich.
It took days for the police to get
the city back under control,
and by then any trace of Gregson
was buried.
They've found him now, of course -
or what's left of him.
It's too horrible to think about.
At least they've locked Hitler up
for five long years.
Coombs says he won't serve
five years, or anything like it.
There's another thing.
Edith inherits Gregson's publishing
company. I think I expected that.
I hope, somehow, it helps her
get through this.
It was very generous of him.
I suppose they loved each other.
Oh, poor Edith.
How is she taking it?
Hard to say.
It wasn't a surprise, of course.
But there's always a shred of hope,
isn't there? Shall I go and see her?
She's gone for a walk.
She wanted to be on her own.
I'm sorry, Milady, I'm afraid
it's not convenient just now.
L-I only want a moment.
As I said, it's not convenient.
What's this?
I don't want her to come in.
Well, there's no need to be rude.
Of course not.
Well, she's not coming in -
and that's flat.
I'm trying to bring her around, but
I wish you hadn't jumped the gun.
I know, but I had some bad news today
and I needed to see her.
You mean you were right about
Marigold's father?
I'm very sorry to hear it.
But if you could just give me some
time. I don't have time, Mr Drewe.
Of course I'm sorry, but let's face
it - he's been dead for over a year.
That's when he went missing.
Yes, but he didn't die for
Lady Edith until this afternoon.
That's what matters, isn't it?
I suppose so.
What are you studying now, Daisy?
The War of the Spanish Succession.
Oh. As a matter of fact, I'm Ve...
Very what, Mr Molesley?
Er... Oh, never mind.
Ohh... I'm sorry to disturb
Your Ladyship. What is it, Spratt?
We are having rather a problem
with Miss Denker.
She does not seem to grasp
the laundry arrangements here.
She wants it all to go to the big
house, even the... smaller items.
You're losing your sense of
the appropriate, Spratt.
You're losing your sense of occasion.
But she's back there
in the kitchen now,
shouting at the top of her voice,
and refusing to wash your... things.
Well, I'm sure this is
all very interesting to Mrs Crawley.
I'm sorry, Milady, but I can't
help it. May I send her in?
I do apologise. Oh, don't.
I'm enjoying it immensely.
Oh, that's what I was afraid of.
Are you going to the picnic at Canningford
Grange on Saturday? I think I might.
Oh, I'm glad, because...
No, never mind.
What were you going to say?
Only that I've asked
Lord Merton to tea tomorrow.
Have you decided at last?
Yes, I think so. Oh.
But please don't pester me.
- I'll let you know on Saturday.
- Oh.
I'm having rather a problem
with Mr Spratt, Milady.
I do not know if Miss Collins
pandered to him,
but he seems to have no knowledge of
the proper role of a lady's maid.
Well, we all pander to Spratt
in this house, Denker.
He rules us with a rod of iron.
All except me, Milady.
But I see you have company, so we'll
discuss this at some other time.
And you wonder why I have
neither lady's maid nor butler.
When I've done these,
I might go back to the cottage
and read until our dinner.
Madge says Lady Edith is
dreadfully cut up,
and it's extra hard because
he was killed so long ago.
And I suppose she can't expect the
whole household to go into mourning
when he was no relation
and he's been dead for so long.
Will you please tell me
what is the matter?
I couldn't find your button box.
I'd forgotten all about it.
Oh, well, never mind.
It'll turn up. I did look.
I looked in all the cupboards,
and I found some other things.
Oh, yes? Yes.
I found a book by Marie Stopes
and a box containing
a cunning piece of equipment
to ensure there would be
no Baby Bates.
And I'm supposed to applaud your
poking around in my things, am I?
Now, just a minute. It is not for
you to be angry with me -
it is for me to be angry with you.
How do you make that out?
You tell me
you are longing for a child,
that it's in the hands of God,
but you seem to have
put it in the very practised hands
of Miss Stopes.
You're wrong. It's not like that.
Then what is it like?
Come in, Lily.
I'll leave these on the table
for you.
Ah, Daisy, there you are. I wondered
if you'd like to borrow this.
What is it? The fifth volume of
The Cambridge Modern History.
My dad gave me the whole set
for my 40th birthday.
I don't know.
I've got so many books already.
Don't be churlish.
Mr Molesley's offering to lend you
one of his prized possessions.
There's a good chapter on the war
and politics in Queen Anne's reign.
But if it's not interesting to you,
I quite understand.
No, I will look at it. Thank you.
He's very kind, you know.
We should always be polite
to people who are kind.
There's not much of it about.
What have you told Bates?
Nothing.
And he hasn't asked why you're
sleeping in here? Certainly not.
I wondered if you might like to
change your mind and come back.
You heard Mr Bricker say he was
not in my room by my invitation.
How do I know that wasn't
just his gallantry?
Because I'm telling you.
Nothing happened.
I'll tell you what did happen. You
allowed him into your private life.
A man who thought he could
step into my place, just like that.
He thought it - and he was mistaken.
Very well. If you can honestly say
you have never let a flirtation
get out of hand since we married,
if you have never given a woman
the wrong impression,
then by all means stay away.
Otherwise, I expect you
back in my room tonight.
But why me?
What have I got to do with it?
I wasn't working here
when Mr Green first came.
That's right. She only came -
Thank you, Mrs Hughes.
Even so, we understand
you have some information
concerning Mr and Mrs Bates.
What information?
That's what we hope you'll tell us.
I want to talk about your past.
Would you prefer we were alone?
I can't allow you
to question a maid in this house
without my being present.
Miss Baxter?
Let her stay.
Very well.
When you served your prison
sentence for theft - What?
They released you after three years,
leaving the remaining two years
to lie on the books. Yes.
You know that if you break the terms
of your release,
you can return to prison
without a trial? That seems -
Mrs Hughes, one more interruption
and I will ask you to leave.
You think I know more than I do.
I believe there was an incident
when Mr Green was staying here.
And there may have been a journey
to London that no-one knew about,
but I couldn't swear to any of it.
Not even whether it was
Mr Bates who made the journey?
Not even that.
Thanks for your help, Miss Baxter.
Who told you I knew anything?
We had a letter.
From whom?
Good day, Mrs Hughes.
I am going to ask one question.
Does Her Ladyship know your story?
Yes, she knows everything.
Then we'll say no more about it.
Come and see these.
Oh, yes,
this is just the kind of work
we're looking for, isn't it?
I knew you'd say that.
Why? They'd cost the most.
And these designs? They'd be
much cheaper. Much nastier.
A lot of the renovated cottages will
be occupied by lifetime tenants.
We'd have no real income
for 2O years.
So instead of Mr Wavell's horrid houses, we'll
make our own? Tom's protecting the estate.
What's the matter, darling?
She's very listless.
I wonder if she's picked up a germ?
She'd have eaten a dead squirrel
or something equally fell.
She's quite fat. Perhaps she's
pregnant. No, she can't be.
So, what do we say about
these drawings?
I suppose we should go for the
cheaper option, but it's a shame.
Anyway, I must fly. I've got
an appointment in York in an hour.
Mrs Hughes,
have you seen Miss Baxter?
It's not like you to seek her
company. I'm serious, Mrs Hughes.
It's all right. I heard.
Could I talk with you, please?
Come in here.
I'm sorry about this.
Go on. I can take it.
God in heaven.
I thought it would pass,
but it just keeps getting worse.
I can't sleep.
I'm not surprised.
Help me.
You were always asking if I need
help. Well, now's your chance.
I don't know what to do.
We're going to the doctor,
now, and we'll show him the syringe,
and the liquid you injected, all the
pills you've been taking, all of it.
Follow me down in five minutes,
and we'll meet by the backdoor,
and bring everything with you -
do you understand?
I've done something
that I shouldn't have.
And if you knew what it was, you
wouldn't want to be part of this.
I know what it was.
Now, come down in five minutes.
Ahh.
It is wonderful on you, My Lady.
I hope so. My father will explode.
Mais superbe.
Thank you.
You've made me feel very strong.
Does this cover it?
My Lady is very generous.
At least she can carry it off.
Most of them look like
bald monkeys.
Hold on.
And it won't trouble him further?
Not as long as he stops
poisoning himself.
You've had a look at the things
he brought, then?
You've been injecting yourself
with a solution of saline.
That's not harmful, though, is it?
It obviously wasn't sterilised.
Repeated injections would cause
fever, and abscesses at the site.
I assume this is a course of
treatment you've spent money on?
Yes, a lot of money.
I went to London
for what they call electrotherapy.
And the pills and injections were
supposed to continue the process.
The purpose of which was...?
To change me.
To make me more like other people.
Other men.
Well, I'll not be coy and pretend I
don't understand. Nor do I blame you.
But there is no drug,
no electric shock,
that will achieve what you want.
You mean I've been taken for a mug.
My advice to you, Thomas,
would be to accept the burden that
chance has seen fit to lay upon you.
And to fashion as good a life
as you are able.
Remember - harsh reality is
always better than false hope.
Well, that will give you
a good laugh. It won't.
And I don't expect you
to understand,
but I think it shows you
to be a very brave person.
What?
To inflict such pain on yourself
to achieve your goal.
Think what you
could do in this world
if you just set your mind to it.
You're daft - do you know that?
I must telephone Atticus
to warn him we're all coming.
Ask him for dinner tonight
if he's free.
Could I? I mean, just as a friend.
Well, just as a friend, absolutely.
I wish Isis would perk up.
I might ask Stapeley
to have a look at her.
It can't hurt.
I think it's very nice, very solid.
Oh, I hope it is solid,
at this price.
What's the kitchen like? Oh,
not quite the scale you're used to.
Well, I wouldn't mind -
it'd be my own.
I could live here later
when I stopped working.
There's only one flight of stairs,
so I'm sure I could manage that,
no matter how old I get.
Oh, an outside privy, I see.
That'll bring back memories.
Well, Lord knows
I've seen one of them before.
But 'appen I could change things
round when I move in.
I'm sure you could.
Well, that's it. I'm going to take
it. Now, if you'll come outside,
I'll take the key back
and give him my answer.
I envy her.
Have you ever thought about
your life in retirement?
Who says I'll live to retire?
Is everybody ready? What is this?
Oh, it's my cousin Mary.
She says she's got a surprise
for us. You'll love her.
I intend to love everybody.
Ready or not, I'm coming in.
Pola Negri comes to Yorkshire.
Well, we really are
living in the modern world.
Golly, I'm jealous.
Mary, this is Atticus Aldridge.
At last, Mr Aldridge.
Rose has talked of nothing else.
Oh, she's only teasing. Can't I take
it as a compliment?
Granny, what do you think?
Oh. It is you.
I thought it was a man
wearing your clothes.
It suits you.
Papa, do you agree?
It's certainly just the sort of
thing I would expect of you.
I suppose you disapprove?
Not especially.
I'm just amazed that even you
would choose the day after I learn
the man I love is dead
to try out a new fashion.
I don't believe that's quite fair.
And you've planned a jolly picnic
for Saturday.
Am I really expected to join in?
Hopefully not,
as you usually spoil everything.
Huh. Yes, I do.
It seems I do.
Goodnight, Mama.
I'll have a tray in my room.
I'm sorry, Mr Aldridge, but you
might as well know what we're like.
Poor darling. She's so unhappy. She
hasn't clapped eyes on him in years.
She must have known long ago
he was dead - we all did.
But should we go on Saturday?
Please don't cancel.
Rose and I are going,
whether you're coming or not.
Maybe it would be good for her to
have time on her own to think.
All this endless thinking.
It's very overrated.
Oh, Aunt Violet, I do love you.
I blame the war. Before 1914, nobody
thought about anything at all.
But what would I want
with such a thing?
I'll tell you.
It's quite simple.
To avoid bearing my child.
How can you believe that...
when it's all I've ever dreamed of?
Because you think I'm a murderer.
What are you saying?
We know how Vera died.
Not Vera.
But...
...Mr Green.
How long have you known it was him?
I've known since the first day
I heard that it happened.
You can't have. You may have
suspected, but you didn't know.
I knew when he came back.
I knew when he said
he went down to the kitchens
during the concerts.
And I kept telling myself you didn't
know, so it couldn't have been you.
Who killed him, you mean?
I wanted to.
I was going to.
I went into York very early, and
I bought a return ticket to London.
I planned to get there and back
in the same day.
I went onto the platform,
but I never got onto the train.
Because I knew...
...if I saw him,
I would have killed him.
And if I killed him...
I would hang.
I couldn't do that to you.
Thank God.
The next day, when I heard what had
happened, it was like...
the hand of fate.
I had the ticket in my coat pocket,
like a talisman.
What for?
Because if I'd have travelled,
I'd...
I would've handed in both halves.
The fact that it was in my pocket,
untorn, was proof
that I never travelled.
Which is why you were so angry
when I gave it to Mrs Hughes.
If the clerk in York
remembers selling me
a return ticket to London,
I'm a dead man.
Why are you smiling?
Because you're innocent.
I have lived in such fear...
...and such trembling,
and all the while
I couldn't tell you why.
And now I'm just so happy.
Mad as it sounds, I'm so happy.
What do you make of Lady Mary's hair?
They were all talking about it.
I hope she comes down to show us.
Miss Bunting
loved the new hairstyles.
She said women were being set free.
I'm sorry Miss Bunting's gone.
She gave me such confidence.
She'd tell me how sharp I was,
how quick.
I agree with her.
It's harder on your own,
harder to believe.
Well, could I help?
Not with mathematics, probably,
but I know a bit about history
and I've read a few books. How old
were you when you left school? 12.
It was a shame, really.
I was quite bright.
And my dad wanted me to stay on.
He thought I could be a teacher,
if that doesn't make you laugh.
But he couldn't manage it.
We had no money, you see,
and then my mother got ill and
so I had to earn as soon as I could.
Why don't you take Matric now?
No, I've missed it.
But I'd like to help.
Make sure somebody got away.
Mrs Hughes?
Do you remember that overcoat
I gave you, for the refugees,
when we were in London
for Lady Rose's ball?
I do. They were very glad of it.
It sounds mad, I know,
but did you find a ticket in it,
in the pocket?
Of course. You won't remember.
No, I do.
I did find one, a return to London.
That's it.
Come...
You see,
Mr Bates does know
that it was Mr Green. Oh, my Lord!
But he didn't do it, Mrs Hughes.
I know that now.
And if we had that ticket
we could prove it.
We could prove that he never went to
London. I don't understand. How?
Because it wasn't torn.
Of course, you threw it out.
Why wouldn't you?
I must have done. I'm so sorry.
It's not your fault. It's mine.
I gave it away.
I gave away the proof of
my husband's innocence.
Come on,
get your pies, get your pies!
Well, I think you are very brave.
Brave? I'm petrified. I don't even
know the horse I'm riding.
How long is the course?
Three miles.
Twice round a course of
a mile-and-a-half.
To where you can see
that steeple over there.
Well, hello.
What on earth are you doing here?
What do you think?
Riding the point-to-point.
Won't someone introduce us? This is
Mabel Lane Fox. Lord Grantham.
Where are you staying? Last night
I was with the Lawsons at Brough,
but they're away tonight
so I'll head back to London.
What a trek. You'll be exhausted.
Stay with us. Lord Gillingham
and Mr Blake will be there.
Have you brought enough clothes?
Oh, I think so. I know so.
Are you riding?
What's this? Where have you been?
Mr Aldridge and I fixed it last night. His
nice parents let me change at the house.
I do wish you'd call me Atticus.
I admire you.
It'd be a poor show not to ride at
our own event. Quite right.
I shall cheer you on. What about
you? When did you decide to ride?
Yesterday, when I was having my hair
done in York. What about a horse?
Stephen rode Trumpeter over earlier.
They're down by the starting post.
This does seem like too much of
a coincidence. Are you stalking me?
I shall ignore that as I'd
hate to think of you as a vain man.
Well, you certainly know
how to surprise.
That sounds like a compliment.
I must say hello to Charles.
Well done. You seem to have
got things off to a good start.
What would you have done if Lady
Grantham hadn't asked me to stay?
I'd have suggested it myself.
Oh, I thought you'd gone with them.
No, I've a lot to do. To be honest,
it's not really my thing.
Are you going out again? No.
I've a new tenancy contract to check,
and I want to go through the figures
for the repair shop.
You see, I'm going away.
I didn't know that.
No, well, I haven't told anybody.
I don't understand.
You don't have to, but when they get
back, tell them my mind was made up
and I wasn't hysterical or anything.
And give them my love.
Oh, God, Edith.
Won't you wait
and talk to them about it?
If I talked to anyone, it'd be you.
Then talk to me, please.
I can't.
But good luck.
You're a fine man, Tom.
You mustn't let them
flatten that out of you.
Won't you tell me where you're going?
Or can't I at least drive you
somewhere? No.
But I will take one of the cars
to the station
and leave the keys
with the station master.
I just wish -
I can't stay, Tom,
not if I'm ever
going to be happy at all.
It's lunacy! You've lost your mind!
Tell her.
It's true.
Marigold's her daughter.
It's a lie!
I don't know
what she's holding over you,
but you can't
let her get away with it!
I have a copy of
her birth certificate.
It's in French, but you can read
my name. Which was brave of you.
My aunt wanted me to use a false one, but I
knew I might need proof. Give that to me!
I have others. You've cooked this up
between you. That's enough.
We've nothing formal that gives us
any claim over her.
Only a note from her dying father.
Which I wrote.
How could you do this?
I'm your wife, yet you have lied and
cheated and used me shamefully.
If you'd have taken a mistress
you couldn't have been more false.
Mrs Drewe, I know you don't want to
hear this, but I'm very grateful.
No, I don't bloody want to hear it!
Fetch her things.
I will not!
Then don't.
- No! No! No!
- No...
My baby. No...
There we go.
Wait! just wait, wait.
Wait.
She'll not sleep, else.
Don't be afraid, my darling...
This nice lady is your new mummy.
She loves you,
more than anyone else could.
But don't you forget...
...that we love you, too.
Best of luck!
Let me not fall in front of Rose.
I'm glad her opinion matters.
I'd rather not look a fool quite
yet. She can discover it gently.
I'm dying to ride astride.
Why don't you?
Not if my grandmother's watching.
You surprise me.
You seem more than able
to choose which laws to keep and
which to break. Don't be spiky,
when I only want what you want.
Which is?
For you and Tony to walk into the
sunset together. I do resent you.
I resent your ability to take him
off me, when I know how to make him
happy, and I certainly love him more
than you do. That's all true.
Then why turn up looking like a
cross between a Vogue fashion plate
and a case of dynamite?
I can't make it too easy for him.
They're just about ready to go.
Can I have a look, Donk?
Can you see Aunt Mary?
Yes.
I think she's splendid.
I think she's cracked.
It's good to do some crazy things
when you're young.
As long as you survive them.
Some do crazy things
all their lives. Hmm.
What answer did you give?
I'm going to tell them
when we're all together.
You won't give me away?
You mean you've accepted him? Huh.
I know you'll think me foolish,
but I feel it's my last chance
of a new adventure before I'm done.
Huh. Well, now you've accepted him,
you'll hear no more argument from me.
Go on!
Go, Atticus, go!
Come on, faster!
Tony!
You might have allowed her to be
the first woman. Nonsense.
I don't believe in
letting people win.
Even if it's in your own interest?
Mm-hm. You rode well.
If I make it across the finishing line
at all it's a miracle, as far as
I'm concerned. Nonsense.
You're a positive centaur.
See? He's nearly there - if you'd
just stop jerking his lead.
Well done, but thank God you're all
back in one piece. Who's this?
My parents. Mother, Father, this is
Lord and Lady Grantham.
Lady Mary you already know.
Lord Gillingham, Mabel Lane Fox,
Charles Blake and, of course, Rose.
Lady Rose,
how lovely to see you again.
Come back to the house to bathe
and change.
I'm going to leave it until we get
back to Downton, but thank you.
I can't tempt you
to stay for dinner?
Not today. We're covered in dust.
Come to Downton tomorrow for dinner.
That seems rather an imposition.
Not at all.
Then we'd be delighted.
You haven't met my mother-in-law and our
cousin, Mrs Crawley. Good afternoon.
If the parents of Rose's young man
are coming for dinner,
things must be
more advanced than I realised.
He seems a nice boy, and it's not
like the Catholics, is it?
She won't be expected to convert.
Con... Convert to what?
Judaism.
I read in an article, Lord Sinderby
is a leading figure
in the Jewish community.
There's always something,
isn't there?
What do you mean, gone?
She's gone.
She didn't say where, but I doubt
it's to Lady Rosamund's. Why?
Of course she was very upset about
Gregson, but why run off?
I think I'll slip away, Carson.
ls the car still outside?
They're just unloading it now,
My Lady. I'll - You stay here.
I can manage.
Could you take those two down?
Yes.
Whose cases are these? Lady Mary's.
They're her riding things.
These are Miss Lane Fox's.
If you could take them in.
Home, please. Can you
first stop at Yew Tree Farm?
Yes, Milady.
Lady Edith has taken off.
What do you mean? She's gone.
She left her car at the station.
Mr Branson's walking down there now
to pick it up.
Oh, it must have been
the news from Germany. Tsk.
Poor thing. Well, I ought to
go and ring the gong.
Hm.
Mrs Hughes,
may I make a suggestion that I think
you'll find a strange one,
but I ask that you consider,
none the less.
Heavens. I'm all agog.
Do you think that we should... um...
...invest in a property together?
What on earth do you mean?
I was thinking, if Mrs Patmore
can do it, then we might buy
somewhere jointly,
as a business venture, mind,
spruce it up
and share the rental income.
We'd have a tidy sum
by the time we retired.
Go and ring that gong.
Well, so the birds have flown?
I won't say anything about it,
Your Ladyship. Not to anyone.
Nor will she.
Do you know where she's gone?
No.
Well, thank you so much,
Mr Drewe, Mrs Drewe.
I mustn't take up
any more of your valuable time.
They'll bring a cot for
the young 'UN, madam.
Ring down if there's anything else.
I will do. Thank you.
Oh.
Thank you.
Well, we're together, darling.
I know it's not ideal, but it's such
an improvement on being apart
that I think we should celebrate.
I'll order ice cream,
and a glass of Champagne,
and we'll be as jolly as you like.
Yes?
I'll see you at dinner.
Not if I see you first.
Atticus seems to be very taken with
your niece.
I have a little announcement.
Are you sure?
I've got used to having a companion.
Your positions have changed.
We're all thinking of a different
future, whether we want to or not.
Kiss me. What?
Kiss me - now.
Subtitles by MemoryOnSmells
http://UKsubtitles.ru.